KARLA WUBBENHORST

54 Raspberry Lane, Guelph, ON N1E 7H5 (519 803 0075) kwubbenhorst@yahoo.ca

PROFILE

Knowledgeable and dedicated theological educator with 4 years' experience teaching and forming ministry candidates in top UK, US and Canadian universities and seminaries. Seasoned PCC minister with 15 years' experience of congregational ministry and wider denominational work. Specialist in Christian Doctrine and Ethics, Reformed Theology and Spirituality, and Contemporary Pastoral Formation. Published writer and presenter in academic and ecclesiastical forums. Creative designer of programmes and curricula. Caring toward students, and a valued, committed contributor to the work of any team.

EXPERIENCE

MINISTER — WESTMINSTER-ST.PAUL'S PRESBYTERIAN CHURCH, GUELPH 2005-2020

- Adaptively led this 75-member faith community across 15 years.
- · Weekly preparation and presentation of high-quality, Christ-centred worship
- Leadership of future visioning, missional imagination and stragetic planning
- Wedding and funeral work, pastoral counselling
- Christian education for adults and youth, including curriculum design
- management of the church's social media presence, and design of its publications,
- Presbytery involvement, including 2 interim moderatorships, extensive committee convenership and participation, moderatorship in 2010-11.
- Denominational involvement, including extensive work in writing doctrine for the PCC's Church Doctrine Committee 1997 to 2010 and 2016 to the present.

LECTURER — MCGILL UNIVERSITY/PRESBYTERIAN COLLEGE, MONTREAL (2004-5)

- Taught "Church History 1300 to the present" at McGill's Faculty of Religious Studies for Presbyterian, Anglican and United Church MDiv students (and other McGill students).
- ◆ Taught "Denominational Studies" (Church, Ministry, Sacraments, Creeds and Confessions, Reformed Spirituality, and Reformed Tradition) at Presbyterian College.
- Taught the courses "Reformed Spirituality" and "Applied Christian Ethics" to students registered in Presbyterian College's Diploma in Lay Education.
- Shared with other faculty in evaluation of Presbyterian College students and communication with Presbyteries re: academic progress and ministry fitness.

LECTURER — ABERDEEN UNIVERSITY, SCOTLAND (2001-04)

- Taught/supervised "Christian Doctrine and Practice," "Christian Ethics," "Patristic Theology," "Scottish Theology" and the Honours Dissertation to BTh, MRE and MTh students.
- Served as programme co-ordinator on behalf of Aberdeen University for the joint Pittsburgh Theological Seminary/University of Aberdeen DMin, and taught "Reformed Worship" and "Theological and Ethical Issues Facing the Church," courses at PTS.
- ◆ In fulfilment of research expectations, gave a paper at the Rutherford House Dogmatics conference on Calvin's doctrine of justification in 2003 which was later published as a chapter in *Justification in Perspective*, ed. Bruce McCormack, Baker Academic, 2006.

• Served as academic adviser for students in different degree programmes throughout the University of Aberdeen, and as workplace safety officer within the Divinity School.

SHORT-TERM MINISTRY AND TEACHING ROLES (1995-2000 AND 2020)

- ◆ 2020 ESL Tutor. 10 classes of pre-intermediate and upper intermediate English to EFL learners from Poland. Classes delivered online using Zoom and Googledocs.
- ◆ 2000-2001 Tutor. University of Edinburgh for two courses: "Christian Thought and Contemporary Life" (level 1) and "Systematic Theology" (level 2)
- * 2000 Spring Semester. Tutor. University of Aberdeen for two courses: "Reformation Thought" (level 2) and "Introduction to Practical Theology" (the latter through UofA's distance education dept. on whiteboard).
- 1998-2000 Associate pastor. Kirk of St. Nicholas, Church of Scotland, Aberdeen.
- 1997 and 1998 Summer missionary. Papa Westray, Orkney Islands, Scotland. Remote.
- 1997-98 Ministry internship, St. Andrew's St. Lambert, QC, bilingual milieu.
- 1995 Summer ministry student. Iona Presbyterian Church, Dartmouth, N.S.

EDUCATION

- DMin 2022 expected graduation. Westminster Theological Seminary, Philadelphia Dissertation is on catechesis for disciple-making. Applied research project is a modern version of the confirmation class. Course work has a pastoral counselling focus.
- ♦ PhD incomplete. University of Edinburgh. Scotland. Thesis had the working title Calvin's Theological Anthropology: Reformed trinitarian realism in the idiom of the image. Grants: the SSHRC doctoral fellowship, the Overseas Research Scholarship ORS among others.
- MDiv 1998; with distinction from Presbyterian College/MTS at McGill. Received the Calvin Gold Medal at graduation and various other prizes in course.
- Grad DipCS 1996; Regent College. Received full scholarship at Regent.
- BA 1995; first class honours in Classics. University of King's College/Dalhousie University. Halifax, N.S. Received substantial scholarships upon entrance and throughout the degree.

SKILLS, CERTIFICATIONS AND INTERESTS

- CELTA. TEFL certification regulated by Cambridge Assessement.
- Young Children and Worship teacher's certification.
- Prepare-Enrich Marriage counselling certification.
- Competent in MSOffice suite and Mac equivalent; video and photo editing (Mac&PC). Youtube, facebook, wordpress capable. Zoom, Moodle, & Google classroom capable.
- Languages: French (decent), German (some), NT Greek still good, Latin rusty.
- World nomad. Shutter bug. Home chef. Gardening bore. Film/Theatre buff. Renaissance chorister/Folkie.

REFERENCES

The Rev. Dr. John Vissers, Principal, Knox College, Toronto
The Rev. Alex MacLeod, Minister, Kortright PC, Guelph
Elspeth Singh, Elder, Westminster-St. Paul's Church, Guelph
519 836 5637
john.vissers@utoronto.ca
alex@kortrightchurch.org
elspethsingh@icloud.com